<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Victoria Kafifi</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/victoriakafifi/feed/?simply_static_page=510" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 19:24:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Barbie Dolls Redefining Representation</title>
		<link>/barbie-dolls-redefining-representation/</link>
					<comments>/barbie-dolls-redefining-representation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 18:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[creative industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultural education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[represenataion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=77</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I was a little girl, I played with dolls, and my first Barbie had blonde hair and blue eyes. I expressed my sense of style by creating...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When I was a little girl, I played with dolls, and my first Barbie had blonde hair and blue eyes. I expressed my sense of style by creating clothes for the doll and styling it. Additionally, I used to create a dream board in the form of a journal that I carried with me every day to play with and immerse myself in my own imaginary dream world. The images in my book never represented me, because I cut them out of glossy magazines and pasted them into my Dream Home Playbook. Psychologically, this concept of a future self is crucial for a child&#8217;s development, providing motivation, hope, and a sense of worth, all of which children begin to develop as young as two or three.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="744" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_4419-scaled-e1704651506629-1024x744.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-80" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_4419-scaled-e1704651506629-1024x744.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_4419-scaled-e1704651506629-300x218.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_4419-scaled-e1704651506629-768x558.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_4419-scaled-e1704651506629-1536x1116.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_4419-scaled-e1704651506629-973x707.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_4419-scaled-e1704651506629-508x369.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_4419-scaled-e1704651506629.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">With my niece Vale, I resemble her exactly when I was a child.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Returning to my childhood narrative, the unfortunate truth was that Barbie dolls, Disney films, superheroes, and images of models or ordinary people endorsing various brands on television or in magazines did not depict individuals like me. Even the middle pages from magazines that I used to paste in my room did not feature people of colour. If a child never encounters someone resembling them in the media or on their toys, portrayed as beautiful, smart, or talented, how are they supposed to cultivate a healthy sense of self? My contention is that most children grow up with exposure to television, modelling, glossy magazines, deriving significant confidence from these sources. It is essential for all of us to see ourselves represented in magazines, television and in the mainstream media, .</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="720" height="900" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/victoriakafifi_116661717_3319531804765125_2057183255796138264_n.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/victoriakafifi_116661717_3319531804765125_2057183255796138264_n.jpg 720w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/victoriakafifi_116661717_3319531804765125_2057183255796138264_n-240x300.jpg 240w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/victoriakafifi_116661717_3319531804765125_2057183255796138264_n-508x635.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></figure>



<p>It is crucial to acknowledge that representation fosters unity in society. The absence of representation establishes an unconscious divide, leading to superiority and segregation in society. For instance, a racially charged hashtag, #NotMyAriel, trended on Twitter, when Halle Bailey made history as the first Black actress to portray Ariel in The Little Mermaid. However, parents capturing the reactions of young Black children, who were astonished and overjoyed by this new Ariel, overshadowed the hate from cyberbullying. On a positive note, Barbie has embraced this change, featuring over 200 careers and counting, continuously inspiring the limitless potential in every little girl. They celebrate heroes like Katherine Johnson, a pioneer in math and science, who broke barriers by making critical calculations for the success of sending astronauts to the moon. Disney and various other branches of media are beginning to embrace diversity.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="675" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/dolls-e1704655218553-675x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-84" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/dolls-e1704655218553-675x1024.jpg 675w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/dolls-e1704655218553-198x300.jpg 198w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/dolls-e1704655218553-768x1165.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/dolls-e1704655218553-508x771.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/dolls-e1704655218553.jpg 861w" sizes="(max-width: 675px) 100vw, 675px" /></figure>



<p>I am incredibly proud of women of colour such as Adwoa Aboah, Yara Shahidi, and Gabby Douglas for leveraging their platforms to impact the upcoming generation of women. They are demonstrating that girls can aspire to be anything they want, inspiring limitless potential and working to bridge the Dream Gap. Congratulations to Malenga Mulendema from Zambia for creating the first African children&#8217;s animated show for both TV and the movie streaming service Netflix. Titled &#8220;Mama K’s Team 4,&#8221; the show depicts the adventures of an all-girl spy team and is produced by Triggerfish Animation Studios in South Africa. This groundbreaking production provides a unique opportunity for a new generation of African children to witness characters they can relate to, portraying powerful and aspirational role models on-screen.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="718" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/doll-e1704655255244-718x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-85" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/doll-e1704655255244-718x1024.jpg 718w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/doll-e1704655255244-210x300.jpg 210w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/doll-e1704655255244-768x1096.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/doll-e1704655255244-973x1388.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/doll-e1704655255244-508x725.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/doll-e1704655255244.jpg 1029w" sizes="(max-width: 718px) 100vw, 718px" /></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/barbie-dolls-redefining-representation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty</title>
		<link>/julien-macdonald-obe-celebrates-authentic-beauty/</link>
					<comments>/julien-macdonald-obe-celebrates-authentic-beauty/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[creative industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion shows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London Fashion Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During London Fashion Week, I had the privilege of meeting renowned designers, and one who particularly made an epic return this season was Julien Macdonald. An internationally acclaimed...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>During London Fashion Week, I had the privilege of meeting renowned designers, and one who particularly made an epic return this season was Julien Macdonald. An internationally acclaimed British fashion designer, Julien Macdonald OBE, pursued fashion knitwear at the University of Brighton and earned his MA at the Royal College of Art in London. This award-winning designer has adorned celebrities such as Mariah Carey, Beyoncé, Naomi Campbell, Rihanna, and more. Julien Macdonald&#8217;s latest collection, titled &#8220;Julien x Gabriela,&#8221; is a collaboration with socialite Gabriela Gonzalez.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="798" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8839.png" alt="Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty" class="wp-image-116" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8839.png 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8839-241x300.png 241w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8839-508x633.png 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty</figcaption></figure>



<p>This season&#8217;s event unfolded as a star-studded fashion spectacle. Izabel Goulart, a former Victoria&#8217;s Secret model, kicked off the show, and the other models showcased dazzling knit gowns, jumpsuits, and swimwear adorned with sparkling sequins and knit mesh. The essence of this new collection is to commemorate womanhood, embracing diversity, and celebrating a variety of body shapes and sizes.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="777" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8966.jpg" alt="Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty" class="wp-image-112" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8966.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8966-247x300.jpg 247w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8966-508x617.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty</figcaption></figure>



<p><br>The British Fashion Council has been promoting awareness of Positive Fashion. Julien Macdonald is dedicated to sustainable fashion practices, incorporating organic fabrics and maintaining environmental consciousness. He also want a better representation of diverse woman on the Catwalk.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="799" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/34AE9546-17ED-43EB-8CBB-92105558C619.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-114" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/34AE9546-17ED-43EB-8CBB-92105558C619.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/34AE9546-17ED-43EB-8CBB-92105558C619-240x300.jpg 240w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/34AE9546-17ED-43EB-8CBB-92105558C619-508x634.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Myself with Model Emilia boateng</figcaption></figure>



<p>The British Fashion Council (BFC), recognises that the fashion industry engages consumers daily. Therefore, through the Institute of Positive Fashion (IPF), their aim is to create an industry blueprint by bringing together expertise from different areas to help brands with a platform designed to celebrate industry best practice and encourage future business decisions to create positive change.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="853" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8928.png" alt="" class="wp-image-115" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8928.png 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8928-225x300.png 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8928-508x677.png 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">With the British Designer Ozwald Boateng and his daughter Emilia boateng</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/julien-macdonald-obe-celebrates-authentic-beauty/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Exquisite Fashion Show by Paul Costelloe</title>
		<link>/the-exquisite-fashion-show-by-paul-costelloe/</link>
					<comments>/the-exquisite-fashion-show-by-paul-costelloe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Let me acquaint you with another prominent figure, namely Paul Costelloe. He stands as one of the most well-established figures in British and Irish Fashion, renowned for his...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Let me acquaint you with another prominent figure, namely Paul Costelloe. He stands as one of the most well-established figures in British and Irish Fashion, renowned for his utilization of handcrafted, opulent fabrics intertwined with cutting-edge design, innovation, and creativity. He pursued his education at the École d&#8217;Chambre Syndicale de la Haute Couture, Paris, from 1968 to 1969.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="634" height="429" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20190922-WA0013-e1704719754919.jpg" alt="The Exquisite Fashion Show by Paul Costelloe" class="wp-image-106" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20190922-WA0013-e1704719754919.jpg 634w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20190922-WA0013-e1704719754919-300x203.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20190922-WA0013-e1704719754919-508x344.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 634px) 100vw, 634px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Myself with Paul Costelloe.</figcaption></figure>



<p>The fashion show event for this season took place at the Palm Court in The Waldorf Hilton Hotel. I had the honour of being invited as a front-row guest, and it proved to be an extraordinary display featuring vibrant colours. The new collection emanates a blend of vibrancy, sophistication, effortless femininity, and elegance. The models showcased trendy curls styled by Sharon Tate, presenting a 60s-inspired look that was nothing short of fabulous. Complemented by unique, oversized gold bangles and pearl jewellery from Pebble London, along with powerful and colourful footwear, the entire ensemble was captivating. Personally, I found the shoes particularly delightful. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="799" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-799x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-105" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-799x1024.jpg 799w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-234x300.jpg 234w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-768x984.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-508x651.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956.jpg 809w" sizes="(max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px" /></figure>



<p>In conclusion, the experience served as a reminder to &#8220;keep heels, head, and standards high,&#8221; echoing the timeless words of the late and great Coco Chanel.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="586" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952-586x1024.jpg" alt="The Exquisite Fashion Show by Paul Costelloe" class="wp-image-108" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952-586x1024.jpg 586w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952-172x300.jpg 172w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952-508x888.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 586px) 100vw, 586px" /></figure>



<p>For the grand finale, visit my <a href="https://www.instagram.com/victoriakafifi/" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.instagram.com/victoriakafifi/">https://www.instagram.com/victoriakafifi/</a> for exclusive videos providing an inside look at the highlights of this fantastic event.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-exquisite-fashion-show-by-paul-costelloe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Evolution of Fashion Shows: Age-Inclusive Elegance</title>
		<link>/how-have-fashion-shows-evolved/</link>
					<comments>/how-have-fashion-shows-evolved/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[creative industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion shows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London Fashion Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion show]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johnstons of Elgin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London fashion week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Most Age Diverse Fashion show]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=34</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This season, designers in New York, London, and Milan have subverted industry norms by casting models of various ages in their shows. In regards to age, body size...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Most Age Diverse Season &#x1f44c;&#x1f3ff;" width="620" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pmg96M89Kn4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Johnstons of Elgin Autumn Winter 19 collection</figcaption></figure>



<p></p>



<p>This season, designers in New York, London, and Milan have subverted industry norms by casting models of various ages in their shows. In regards  to age, body size and race, there was a diverse representation on the runway at the Johnston of Elgin fashion show. One lesson this season taught us is that, it is evident that age is merely a number, one to which the fashion industry should no longer conform. </p>



<p></p>



<p>While seasons and influences may change, one constant remains: the quest for beauty and elegance. Johnstons of Elgin creates desirable pieces of art designed to resonate with its customers, precious objects of real beauty that hold great personal meaning in today’s disposable culture.According to Scott, Johnstons of Elign has retained its reputation for quality, artistry,innovation and designs for over two centuries.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">These pillars are the very heart of what they do on a day to day basis and are demonstrated year after year. The Autumn Winter 19 collection exemplifies the brand’s exceptional craftsmanship,including intarsia hand-knitting and 360 digital printing technology.  Johnstons of Elign collection reflects the keen sense of style and understanding of diverse tastes.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Flashes of tartan give a nod to the brand’s proud Scottish heritage, which dates right back to 1797.This sophisticated,elegant and colourful collection proves that Johnstons of Elgin is master of textile innovation and a brand for all seasons. In conclusion, this sophisticated and elegant fashion truly captivated, seamlessly embracing all ages with a timeless and inclusive allure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/how-have-fashion-shows-evolved/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Embracing True Beauty: A Celebration of Authenticity.</title>
		<link>/embracing-true-beauty-a-celebration-of-authenticity/</link>
					<comments>/embracing-true-beauty-a-celebration-of-authenticity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=49</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Authentic beauty can have different meanings among individuals, it’s about being true to one’s true self, embracing imperfections and flaws. Beauty is like art, there are no pieces...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<p>Authentic beauty can have different meanings among individuals, it’s about being true to one’s true self, embracing imperfections and flaws. Beauty is like art, there are no pieces of art that are identical. Similarly, there is no beauty without imperfection, and each individual possesses their own distinctive form of beauty. Therefore, individuals should acknowledge and confidently embrace their imperfections unapologetically, as these imperfections are an integral aspect of beauty. It is important to recognise that each individual possesses intrinsic worth, independent of societal beauty standards that fail to celebrate this uniqueness.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-1024x1024.jpg" alt="London Fashion Week" class="wp-image-51" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-768x768.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-2048x2048.jpg 2048w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-88x88.jpg 88w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-973x973.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-508x508.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">London Fashion Week</figcaption></figure>



<p>Analogous to art, beauty is diverse and attempting to conform to conventional beauty norms is a suppression, denying the diverse expressions of beauty. True beauty begins with self- acceptance, and originates from within, reflecting the essence of your character through the choices you make, how you present yourself, and how you treat others. Therefore, let us celebrate our skills, abilities, talents, intellect rather than placing emphasis on superficial aspects such as body size, skin colour, and conforming to societal beauty standards. In contrast, let us spread awareness and encourage mental fitness and well-being, body positivity, self care, and the importance of human connection. This involves actively engaging in listening, caring, expressing love towards one another.</p>



<p>There should be more celebration and appreciation of the many forms that complete what beauty, including: the acts of kindness, love, respect, honesty and loyalty. Reflecting on cultures throughout history, it becomes evident that beauty can finds its foundation in morality, integrity, kindness, loyalty and faith. These were once universal virtues and values shared collectively. Regrettably, this commonality has waned, at least in widespread acceptance. This is unfortunate because a life without a moral compass, individuals may find themselves adrift. A predicament already faced by many, but let us find solace in the fact that not everyone is lost. As uniquely and beautifully made individuals, we ought to re-embrace the shared values, principles, and faith that were once woven into the fabric of our existence. This is what holds significance and will continue to bind us together. Holding steadfast to the principles of truthfulness, compassion, and forbearance is paramount.</p>





<p>I would assert that authentic beauty is inseparable from true happiness. The act of being loved and accepted for who you are empowers you to embrace your beauty—a state of untarnished joy reminiscent of a child. The right to happiness is inherent to all, and there exists a moral obligation to embrace this birthright. True beauty thrives in the richness of diversity. To quote singer, songwriter, Britt Nicole: “let’s focus on being pretty kind, pretty funny, pretty smart and pretty strong” rather than solely on external appearances.</p>



<p>Additionally, I would appreciate hearing your insight, my beloved readers. What does authentic beauty truly mean to you?</p>



<p>With love Victoria</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/embracing-true-beauty-a-celebration-of-authenticity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating Diversity in Fashion</title>
		<link>/celebrating-diversity-in-fashion/</link>
					<comments>/celebrating-diversity-in-fashion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=71</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a society, we have made significant strides to adapt to changes, embrace diversity, and appreciate individual uniqueness. For example, there is currently a diverse array of models...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As a society, we have made significant strides to adapt to changes, embrace diversity, and appreciate individual uniqueness. For example, there is currently a diverse array of models of colour on the runways, a significant increase from when I initially entered the modelling profession. At the time, it appeared that only one or two spots were available for ethnic models on each runway. A notable shift is occurring, focusing on empowering the next generation of young Black women who were once disregarded but are now being acknowledged and told that they too matter.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1005" height="640" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-66" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1.jpg 1005w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1-300x191.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1-768x489.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1-973x620.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1-508x324.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 1005px) 100vw, 1005px" /></figure>



<p>Increased awareness about diversity and inclusion, especially regarding the representation of women of colour in the fashion industry, has been widely discussed in the mainstream media. However, it&#8217;s crucial to distinguish between desiring inclusion and advocating for a complete overhaul of the exclusive system. Despite the ongoing journey and the need for more efforts, it&#8217;s important to acknowledge and celebrate the positive changes achieved so far.</p>



<p>Thanks to those who paved the way, we can now observe firsthand the transformation taking place in the fashion world. It is a triumph that this transformation is underway, even though it is happening gradually. In the Autumn/Winter 2019 shows, the visibility of the change and its progression seemed more significant, marking a notable shift in the fashion industry towards becoming a more naturally inclusive space, with promising prospects for the future.</p>



<p>Prominent figures, such as Pierpaolo Piccioli, serve as excellent examples of the practical implications of this change. During the couture season in Paris, Piccioli demonstrated a commitment to diversity by predominantly casting black models for his magnificent, colourful, feminine, and stunning Valentino collection. This historic move empowered Black women to confidently embrace their beauty without reservation. The presentation was not just a passing trend but a significant statement and stance, asserting that black women have always been a powerful presence and continue to demonstrate their capability. The myth that women of colour cannot effectively influence and sell has been debunked, as evidenced by the recent elevation of models of colour as cover girls on Vogue magazine.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="799" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0705.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-74" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0705.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0705-240x300.jpg 240w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0705-508x634.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></figure>



<p>Witnessing diverse women featured on the front cover, irrespective of their age, race, abilities, and ethnicity, proved to be genuinely inspiring. I take immense pride in the achievements at British Vogue, where the work underscored the significance of diversity and inclusion within the fashion industry. Appreciation goes to the distinguished Edward Enninful, the editor-in-chief for British Vogue, He truly exemplifies legendary status.</p>



<p>I believe and agree that beauty is diverse, and the fashion industry must acknowledge the influence of showcasing a broader spectrum of beauty. It should serve as a platform for diversity that promotes inclusivity in an exclusive manner. Representation in media and other services is crucial for everyone to see themselves. Brands should also cater to a wide demographic range because when people witness diversity in high fashion modelling, it becomes easier for them to relate to the collections.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/celebrating-diversity-in-fashion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Queen Elizabeth II Award for British Designers</title>
		<link>/queen-elizabeth-ii-award-for-british-designers/</link>
					<comments>/queen-elizabeth-ii-award-for-british-designers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[creative industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion shows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London Fashion Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monarchy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London fashion week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queen Elizabeth II Award for British Designers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the most thrilling moment of my career was meeting her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II. Her Majesty the Queen made an astonishing surprise appearance at London Fashion...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="960" height="720" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830.jpg" alt="Queen Elizabeth II" class="wp-image-42" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830-508x381.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Queen Elizabeth II suprise appearance at London Fashion Week</figcaption></figure>



<p><em>One of the most thrilling moment of my career was meeting her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II. Her Majesty the Queen made an astonishing surprise appearance at London Fashio</em>n week. She was accompanied by Caroline Rush, the Chief Executive of the British Fashion Council, who guided her through the venue, observing presentations of various designers&#8217; collections during London Fashion Week. Her Majesty took the time to visit each designer, engaging in conversations. Her purpose for attending London Fashion Week was to bestow the inaugural Queen Elizabeth 2 Award for British design.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="742" height="512" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Designer.jpg" alt="Queen Elizabeth II" class="wp-image-44" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Designer.jpg 742w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Designer-300x207.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Designer-508x351.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 742px) 100vw, 742px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Queen Elizabeth II, first appearance at London Fashion Week</figcaption></figure>



<p>Seated in the front row alongside Anna Wintour, Vogue&#8217;s editor-in-chief, her presence captivated the crowd, prompting them to rise in greeting. Her Majesty watched the show with a composed demeanor and excitement in her eyes. She adorned herself in an ice-blue skirt suit, complemented by a black handbag, black gloves, and black footwear. She even shared a light-hearted moment with Anna Wintour, resulting in both of them laughing and smiling.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="960" height="720" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-46" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834-508x381.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<p>After the show, in recognition of his achievements, Her Majesty presented Richard Quinn with the inaugural Queen Elizabeth II Award for British Design.The British-born designer is known for specialising in womenswear and printed textiles.Remarkably, he manages a print studio in Peckham, situated in south London, which is accessible to both fellow designers and college students.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="victoriakafifi 1519208985 1719570765898092315 371999188" width="620" height="465" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8ht3cYkiWa4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The Queen engaging with designers</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/queen-elizabeth-ii-award-for-british-designers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
