<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorised Archives - Victoria Kafifi</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/victoriakafifi/category/uncategorised/feed/?simply_static_page=3528" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/uncategorised/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:30:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Connecting With Nature To Recharge Your Energy: My Trip to the Swiss Alps</title>
		<link>/connecting-with-nature-to-recharge-your-energy-my-trip-to-the-swiss-alps/</link>
					<comments>/connecting-with-nature-to-recharge-your-energy-my-trip-to-the-swiss-alps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>January is my birthday month, making it a good time for quiet reflection on how far I have come and acknowledge the successes and failures, as these have...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/connecting-with-nature-to-recharge-your-energy-my-trip-to-the-swiss-alps/">Connecting With Nature To Recharge Your Energy: My Trip to the Swiss Alps</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-left">January is my birthday month, making it a good time for quiet reflection on how far I have come and acknowledge the successes and failures, as these have shaped the woman that I am today. I love the simple things in life and nature is a constant source of joy for me, as it enables me to appreciate the magnificent handiwork of God. This year for the first time I visited Switzerland, where I enjoyed exploring local traditions, cuisine, history and the breathtaking mountain landscapes. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="908" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_familyyyyy-scaled-e1706459346102-1024x908.jpg" alt="A Memorable Adventure in the Swiss Apls" class="wp-image-203" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_familyyyyy-scaled-e1706459346102-1024x908.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_familyyyyy-scaled-e1706459346102-300x266.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_familyyyyy-scaled-e1706459346102-768x681.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_familyyyyy-scaled-e1706459346102-1536x1362.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_familyyyyy-scaled-e1706459346102-973x863.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_familyyyyy-scaled-e1706459346102-508x450.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_familyyyyy-scaled-e1706459346102.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A Memorable Adventure with my daughter and husband</figcaption></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-left">It was my daughter&#8217;s first real experience surrounded by the beauty of high mountains and snow, and this was my first time skiing. Whether seeking adventure, relaxation, or cultural exploration, a holiday to the Swiss Alps offers positive effects both physically and mentally. For me this skii break with my husband and daughter was incredibly relaxing and energising at the same time.</p>



<p><strong>Skiing for the first time</strong></p>



<p>Every time I fell down while skiing, I glanced up at my instructor. It was evident in his eyes that he struggled to suppress laughter, because I was too busy screaming and laughing at myself. Despite my comical flops, he kept a straight face, being all professional and cheering me on to stay calm and focused. And let me tell you, witnessing a 6-foot person &#8220;gracefully&#8221; fall to the ground is a comedy show in itself. It&#8217;s like a slow-motion drop, with long legs and arms flailing in all directions <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="768" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6316-768x1024.jpg" alt="A Memorable Adventure in the Swiss Alps" class="wp-image-188" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6316-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6316-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6316-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6316-973x1297.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6316-508x677.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6316.jpg 1220w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A Memorable Adventure in the Swiss Alps</figcaption></figure>



<p>At the end of this holiday though, I felt I have conquered the mountains, thanks to my instructor expertise, patience, and encouragement. He made all the difference in turning what initially seemed daunting into an enjoyable and unforgettable adventure. I am also grateful to my husband for instilling in me a newfound appreciation for skiing and helping me conquer the initial challenges. Skiing for the first time taught me that every turn and twist is like learning to adapt and overcome challenges. I observed that engaging in these activity not only provides exercise but also promotes cardiovascular health and overall fitness. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Climb mountains not so the world can see you, but so you can see the world </p>
<cite>David McCullough Jr</cite></blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="768" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6323.jpg-skii-1-768x1024.jpeg" alt="A Memorable Adventure in the Swiss Alps" class="wp-image-187" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6323.jpg-skii-1-768x1024.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6323.jpg-skii-1-225x300.jpeg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6323.jpg-skii-1-1152x1536.jpeg 1152w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6323.jpg-skii-1-973x1297.jpeg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6323.jpg-skii-1-508x677.jpeg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_6323.jpg-skii-1.jpeg 1220w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A Memorable Adventure in the Swiss Alps</figcaption></figure>



<p>The early difficulties on the slopes are similar to life&#8217;s challenges, but with practice and staying strong, I gained control, smoothly navigating through the twists and turns. Reaching the bottom of the mountain feels like a victory, similar to my name. Since my childhood, I learned that challenges make us uncomfortable, but they develop virtues such as resilience, perseverance, endurance, and patience. Therefore, with each successful ride down the slopes, one gain confidence to overcome new challenges—whether on the slopes or in life. It all depends on our mindset. </p>



<p><strong>My tips </strong> <strong>for First-Time Skiers</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Invest in good quality technical base layer: thermal leggings under ski pants and a fleece and/or a lightweight insulated vest under your ski jacket.</li>



<li>Invest in good quality waterproof ski jacket and pants.</li>



<li> Ski gloves and socks with a high content of merino wool blended with elastic.</li>



<li>Waterproof boots that are long enough to cover your ankles</li>



<li>Don’t forget your winter hat and <em>ski goggles, Yes, the heat from the sun in the mountains feels like summer</em>time.</li>



<li>In the mountains, you usually burn a lot of energy. So, for a good meal, I recommend having both soup, meat, and of course, always leave some space for desserts. This will leave you satisfied, and the flavours are absolutely delicious.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountians-1-1024x683.jpg" alt="A Memorable Adventure" class="wp-image-201" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountians-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountians-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountians-1-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountians-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountians-1-973x649.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountians-1-508x339.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountians-1.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A Memorable Adventure in the Swiss Alps</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Beautiful Scenery</strong></p>



<p>The Swiss Alps display awe- inspiring and breathtaking landscapes, with crystal clear lakes, stunning mountains views and lush greenery. While in the mountains, I absorbed my surroundings and fully immersed in the moment, surrounded by calm and peaceful environment that helps me feel deeply connected to nature. Additionally, the mountain air, being cleaner and fresher, provides an ideal environment to engage in meditation by concentrating on the breath—taking deep inhalations and exhaling slowly.</p>



<p><strong>Fresh Mountain Air</strong></p>



<p>The air is filled with a pure, refreshing coldness, and the snow is thick, displaying an enchanting white colour. The mountains contain a distinct form of oxygen that made me feel fresher, healthier, and energetic. This holiday was a chance to escape from daily routines, clear the mind, and focus on the present moment because that is all we have; the past is gone, and the future is unknown.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountian-1024x683.jpg" alt="A Memorable Adventure" class="wp-image-200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountian-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountian-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountian-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountian-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountian-973x649.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountian-508x339.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/skii-mountian.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A Memorable Adventure in the Swiss Alps</figcaption></figure>



<p>In conclusion, surrounding ourself with the beauty of nature and immersing in different cultures, can strength health, enrich our intellect and broaden our perspectives. Indeed, I strongly believe that if we respect and understand each other&#8217;s cultures, these facilitates collective learning and foster collaborative efforts that can be employed to solve the problems our world is facing today.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/connecting-with-nature-to-recharge-your-energy-my-trip-to-the-swiss-alps/">Connecting With Nature To Recharge Your Energy: My Trip to the Swiss Alps</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/connecting-with-nature-to-recharge-your-energy-my-trip-to-the-swiss-alps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Arts education-Inspirational interview</title>
		<link>/the-importance-of-arts-education-inspirational-interview/</link>
					<comments>/the-importance-of-arts-education-inspirational-interview/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 14:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the digital age, where technology and AI are changing humans ways of living through automation, nothing will replace Arts. It is evolving with technology and changing the...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-importance-of-arts-education-inspirational-interview/">The Importance of Arts education-Inspirational interview</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the digital age, where technology and AI are changing humans ways of living through automation, nothing will replace Arts. It is evolving with technology and changing the lives of people around the world. Therefore, allow me to present to you an individual in one of the most rewarding career that involves the responsibility of educating the next generation. I was inspired by her passion and dedication for her job, even at the weekend she brought students assignments home from school to mark.</p>



<p>Miss Anouska Armon is an Arts teacher at a secondary school in central London. She have been teaching for seven years and have Bachelor degree in Fine Arts and Education. Miss Armon passion for arts started at the age of 14 and she knew that one day she will pursue a career as an art teacher. Some human experiences or stories can not be communicated through written words alone, but also through other various forms of human expressions including visual arts and performing arts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/a3352688-7e69-4daa-be69-468cf74eb23d-1024x768.jpg" alt="Arts education" class="wp-image-171" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/a3352688-7e69-4daa-be69-468cf74eb23d-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/a3352688-7e69-4daa-be69-468cf74eb23d-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/a3352688-7e69-4daa-be69-468cf74eb23d-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/a3352688-7e69-4daa-be69-468cf74eb23d-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/a3352688-7e69-4daa-be69-468cf74eb23d-973x730.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/a3352688-7e69-4daa-be69-468cf74eb23d-508x381.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/a3352688-7e69-4daa-be69-468cf74eb23d.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Student Arts work</figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>Arts is a natural form of expression from toddler age, for instance, children instinctively pick up pens and put them on paper to draw</em>.</p>
<cite><strong><em>MRS ANOUSKA ARM</em></strong>ON</cite></blockquote>



<p>Art teachers play an important role in nurturing creativity, developing students artistic skills and also contributes to their personal growth. Anouska pointed out that there are different forms to creativity through various medium such as: dance,music,theatre, drawing, painting and sculpture. Therefore, creative thinking can foster curiosity and inquiry, this can also inspire individuals to become great researchers and creators.</p>



<p>Therefore, creativity means many things to her, &#8220;it is an expression such as physical expression through imagination, movement or skills that an individual possess” &#8211;<em>Miss Anouska A</em>rmon.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="768" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6889cb99-2606-4a79-ab06-8dfad28d4fbf-768x1024.jpg" alt="Arts Education" class="wp-image-170" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6889cb99-2606-4a79-ab06-8dfad28d4fbf-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6889cb99-2606-4a79-ab06-8dfad28d4fbf-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6889cb99-2606-4a79-ab06-8dfad28d4fbf-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6889cb99-2606-4a79-ab06-8dfad28d4fbf-973x1297.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6889cb99-2606-4a79-ab06-8dfad28d4fbf-508x677.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6889cb99-2606-4a79-ab06-8dfad28d4fbf.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"> The British Library- Yinka Shonibare</figcaption></figure>



<p>Arts education is also known to foster tranfereable skills in students, including creative thinking, communication skills and problem solving.Therefore, skills gained from the arts education are signicantly important for future employment in different sectors.</p>



<p>The best advice she would like to give to someone who is inspiring to become an art teacher is to have a lot of patience with students and also themselves. She  also advice young people to take risk and never be afraid to make mistakes, because some of the best pieces of art work in galleries were produced through experiments.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>“Always remember that Arts is not limited and there plenty of different </em> <em>options to chose from in the creative sector”.</em></p>



<p><strong>— MRS </strong><strong><em>ANOUSKA </em></strong><strong>ARMON</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="768" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/5b1f617d-c7f1-4b1e-9190-689038599445-768x1024.jpg" alt="Arts Education" class="wp-image-172" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/5b1f617d-c7f1-4b1e-9190-689038599445-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/5b1f617d-c7f1-4b1e-9190-689038599445-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/5b1f617d-c7f1-4b1e-9190-689038599445-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/5b1f617d-c7f1-4b1e-9190-689038599445-973x1297.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/5b1f617d-c7f1-4b1e-9190-689038599445-508x677.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/5b1f617d-c7f1-4b1e-9190-689038599445.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Student Arts work</figcaption></figure>
</blockquote>



<p>In conclusion, the  government should prioritise publicly-funded arts for the cultural and creative sectors, because it is amongst the top 5 industry to drive economic growth in the United Kingdom. For example, according to recent statistics, one in six jobs are provided by London’s culture and<a href="https://www.london.gov.uk/mayor-hails-importance-creative-industries-capital-new-data-shows-one-five-jobs-creative-economy"> creative industries</a>. In contrast, in the mainstream media there have been news about lack of material resources due to funding cuts by the Conservative government. Government-funded arts is significantly important and requires more educators in secondary schools and higher education institution to train young Londoners for success in the cultural and creative sectors.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20180622-WA0021-1024x768.jpg" alt="Creative work of christo and Jeanne-Claude, The London Mastaba" class="wp-image-174" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20180622-WA0021-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20180622-WA0021-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20180622-WA0021-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20180622-WA0021-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20180622-WA0021-973x730.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20180622-WA0021-508x381.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20180622-WA0021.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Creative work of christo and Jeanne-Claude, The London Mastaba </figcaption></figure>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-importance-of-arts-education-inspirational-interview/">The Importance of Arts education-Inspirational interview</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-importance-of-arts-education-inspirational-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Must-Visit Destinations in Namibia</title>
		<link>/must-visit-destinations-in-namibia/</link>
					<comments>/must-visit-destinations-in-namibia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Happy New Year Everyone The holiday season provides us with an opportunity to rest, reflect, and spend quality time with loved ones. I traveled to Namibia, my place...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/must-visit-destinations-in-namibia/">Must-Visit Destinations in Namibia</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Happy New Year Everyone</strong></p>



<p>The holiday season provides us with an opportunity to rest, reflect, and spend quality time with loved ones. I traveled to Namibia, my place of birth and upbringing, for Christmas and New Year. This holiday was particularly special as I returned with my husband and daughter. Namibia  possesses abundant natural resources, with its primary export commodities including raw copper, cut diamonds, gemstones, granite, lead products, marble, uranium, and zinc (<a href="http://www.namibiahc.org.uk/">www.namibiahc.org.uk</a>). The Land of the Brave offers several noteworthy places to visit, and in this post, I will share a few recommendations.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0877-1024x683.jpg" alt="Namibia Adventures" class="wp-image-148" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0877-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0877-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0877-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0877-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0877-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0877-973x649.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0877-508x339.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Namibia Adventures</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Swakopmund</strong></p>



<p>It is an exquisite coastal town adorned with sandy beaches along the Atlantic Ocean, and it is also in proximity to areas that offer adventurous tours featuring activities such as quad-biking, camel riding, sandboarding, and skydiving. During Christmas and New Year&#8217;s Eve, families come together, setting up music and enjoying a beachside barbecue,(known as braai) grilling mouth-watering, delicious meat.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1284-683x1024.jpg" alt="Namibia Adventures" class="wp-image-146" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1284-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1284-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1284-768x1152.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1284-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1284-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1284-973x1460.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1284-508x762.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1284-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Namibia Adventures: Enriching Activities</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Langstrand also known as Longbeach</strong></p>



<p>It is situated between Swakopmund and Walvis Bay, offering a clean, tranquil, and serene residential environment with expansive holiday homes suitable for large families. Our time there was delightful, spent taking walks, observing dolphins play in the distance, and, of course, witnessing the spectacular sunset at the beach.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1100-1-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-163" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1100-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1100-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1100-1-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1100-1-973x649.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1100-1-508x339.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1100-1.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Namibia Adventures: Atlantic Ocean</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Walvisbay</strong></p>



<p>It serves as the primary port town in Namibia, complemented by the presence of Walvis Bay International Airport, although the main international airport in Namibia is Hosea Kutako International Airport. According to Walvis Bay Salt Holdings (WBSH), they are the leading producers of solar sea salt in sub-Saharan Africa, processing 93 million cubic meters of saltwater annually to yield over 900,000 tons of high-quality salt, referred to as white gold (<a href="http://www.unitrans.africa/">www.unitrans.africa</a>). This positions Namibia as one of the largest exporters of salt in Africa, with Western European and North American countries benefiting significantly from these substantial production levels.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0479-1024x683.jpg" alt="Namibia" class="wp-image-152" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0479-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0479-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0479-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0479-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0479-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0479-973x649.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0479-508x339.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">White gold</figcaption></figure>



<p>Walvis Bay is also a habitat for various vibrant and colourful birds, particularly the strikingly long-legged Flamingos, hashtag teamlonglegs. Personally, I affectionately consider them my tribe due to their long necks and legs, which bear a resemblance to mine. Interestingly, my childhood nickname was Flamingo, and though I used to be upset when kids called me that, I now embrace my 6ft height.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0454-1024x683.png" alt="Namibia Adventures" class="wp-image-150" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0454-1024x683.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0454-300x200.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0454-768x512.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0454-973x649.png 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0454-508x339.png 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0454.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Flamingos</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Omaheke region</strong></p>



<p>Located in the eastern part of Namibia, this region is inhabited by the Ovaherero and San People tribes. This region is abundantly scattered with a variety of cattle’s, goats, and sheep’s, as the Herero tribes predominantly engage in farming. Notably, &#8220;the livestock population of Namibia is about 2.5 million cattle, 2.4 million sheep, and 1.8 million goats, with approximately 80% of Namibia’s beef and mutton exported to South Africa and the European Union&#8221; (<a href="http://www.namibiahc.org.uk/">www.namibiahc.org.uk</a>). Moreover, the landscape is lush with nutritious grasslands for the herds to graze, and the sturdy trees yield high-quality hardwood used for fireplaces.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1543-1024x683.png" alt="Namibia" class="wp-image-151" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1543-1024x683.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1543-300x200.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1543-768x512.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1543-973x649.png 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1543-508x339.png 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1543.png 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Omaheke region</figcaption></figure>



<p><br><br></p>
<p>The post <a href="/must-visit-destinations-in-namibia/">Must-Visit Destinations in Namibia</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/must-visit-destinations-in-namibia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uniting Against Racism and Police Brutality</title>
		<link>/uniting-against-racism-and-police-brutality-with-black-lives/</link>
					<comments>/uniting-against-racism-and-police-brutality-with-black-lives/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The recent news that flooded our social media timelines, had a similar impact to an unexpected punch to the stomach, once again highlighting the injustice and racism in...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/uniting-against-racism-and-police-brutality-with-black-lives/">Uniting Against Racism and Police Brutality</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The recent news that flooded our social media timelines, had a similar impact to an unexpected punch to the stomach, once again highlighting the injustice and racism in our societies. The killing of George Floyd has left me profoundly saddened and angered, as he became another victim whose life was unjustly taken and witnessed by people worldwide. George, as he is known by his local neighbours, he was pleading for his life to the same people who are suppose to protect him. For approximately 8 minutes, his voice echoed, yet it was ignored. In this so-called civilized world, no individual deserve to lose their life at the hands of the police through ongoing brutality.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="874" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0979-scaled-e1704899517462-1024x874.jpg" alt="Black lives Matter" class="wp-image-134" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0979-scaled-e1704899517462-1024x874.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0979-scaled-e1704899517462-300x256.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0979-scaled-e1704899517462-768x656.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0979-scaled-e1704899517462-1536x1311.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0979-scaled-e1704899517462-973x830.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0979-scaled-e1704899517462-508x434.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Black lives Matter, end police brutality</figcaption></figure>



<p>I express my solidarity against this despicable crime and this inhumane, senseless act of racism must never be repeated again. Racism is a tangible reality that exists in schools, workplaces, police departments, courts, and various societal institutions. It is crucial for white individuals to recognise and take responsibility for systemic racial discrimination in the USA, UK, and beyond. White supremacy has no place in our world and stands as a significant stain on human history. According to Ann Wojcicki, a genetics researcher at 23andMe, ‘we are more similar than different, sharing 99% of our DNA, regardless of melanin levels’ (<a href="https://www.23andme.com/">https://www.23andme.com/</a>). Therefore, those with less melanin, commonly identified as white people, must acknowledge their privilege and use it to support black people in the ongoing fight against racism.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="820" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6F3A8340-F7E3-4AAD-A7A6-D342DCD05216-820x1024.jpg" alt="Nelson Mandela" class="wp-image-135" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6F3A8340-F7E3-4AAD-A7A6-D342DCD05216-820x1024.jpg 820w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6F3A8340-F7E3-4AAD-A7A6-D342DCD05216-240x300.jpg 240w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6F3A8340-F7E3-4AAD-A7A6-D342DCD05216-768x959.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6F3A8340-F7E3-4AAD-A7A6-D342DCD05216-508x634.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/6F3A8340-F7E3-4AAD-A7A6-D342DCD05216.jpg 828w" sizes="(max-width: 820px) 100vw, 820px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Nelson Mandela</figcaption></figure>



<p>Apartheid and slavery serve as historical lessons from which we must learn, and those who preceded us were executed and unjustly imprisoned in the fight for our human rights. For instance, individuals such as Martin Luther King, Gandhi, and Nelson Mandela faced unjust imprisonment for their courageous stand against racial injustice. I firmly support Martin Luther King&#8217;s famous quote: &#8220;Injustice anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere.&#8221; No individual should face differential treatment based on their skin colour. It is time to put an end to institutional racism and reform the justice system that was historically designed to oppress black people. I am referring to the racially biased policies and practices deeply ingrained in societal institutions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="768" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1009-768x1024.jpg" alt="London protest for Black Lives Matter" class="wp-image-136" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1009-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1009-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1009-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1009-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1009-973x1297.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1009-508x677.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_1009-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">London protest for Black Lives Matter</figcaption></figure>



<p>Regrettably, these incidents are not new; numerous others have lost their loved ones in the same manner. However, what distinguishes the current situation is the recording and sharing of these incidents and crimes against the Black community on social media. The digital platforms are powerful tool in combating injustice and enable our voices to be heard beyond borders. Organizations such as Black Lives Matter advocate for sustainable solutions, affirming the value of Black lives. The enduring suffering from racial discrimination can no longer be ignored, threatening justice and peace globally.</p>



<p>In the words of Michelle Obama: &#8221; It&#8217;s up to all of us: Black, white, everyone, no matter how well meaning we think we might be, to do the honest, uncomfortable work of rooting it out&#8221;. We must stand together as a human race with collective effort to educate each other, support each other and eradicate racism forever. Only than can we live together in harmony and peace. Let us get involve in politics and vote for the change we want to see in our societies. Today, we must not accept living in a reality marked by modern slavery and institutional racism. Let us learn from our younger generation, the children and see all as equal. We all know that racism is taught. Let us love one another as equal belonging to this big family — Humanity.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/uniting-against-racism-and-police-brutality-with-black-lives/">Uniting Against Racism and Police Brutality</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/uniting-against-racism-and-police-brutality-with-black-lives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty</title>
		<link>/julien-macdonald-obe-celebrates-authentic-beauty/</link>
					<comments>/julien-macdonald-obe-celebrates-authentic-beauty/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[creative industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion shows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London Fashion Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>During London Fashion Week, I had the privilege of meeting renowned designers, and one who particularly made an epic return this season was Julien Macdonald. An internationally acclaimed...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/julien-macdonald-obe-celebrates-authentic-beauty/">Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>During London Fashion Week, I had the privilege of meeting renowned designers, and one who particularly made an epic return this season was Julien Macdonald. An internationally acclaimed British fashion designer, Julien Macdonald OBE, pursued fashion knitwear at the University of Brighton and earned his MA at the Royal College of Art in London. This award-winning designer has adorned celebrities such as Mariah Carey, Beyoncé, Naomi Campbell, Rihanna, and more. Julien Macdonald&#8217;s latest collection, titled &#8220;Julien x Gabriela,&#8221; is a collaboration with socialite Gabriela Gonzalez.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="798" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8839.png" alt="Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty" class="wp-image-116" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8839.png 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8839-241x300.png 241w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8839-508x633.png 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty</figcaption></figure>



<p>This season&#8217;s event unfolded as a star-studded fashion spectacle. Izabel Goulart, a former Victoria&#8217;s Secret model, kicked off the show, and the other models showcased dazzling knit gowns, jumpsuits, and swimwear adorned with sparkling sequins and knit mesh. The essence of this new collection is to commemorate womanhood, embracing diversity, and celebrating a variety of body shapes and sizes.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="777" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8966.jpg" alt="Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty" class="wp-image-112" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8966.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8966-247x300.jpg 247w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8966-508x617.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty</figcaption></figure>



<p><br>The British Fashion Council has been promoting awareness of Positive Fashion. Julien Macdonald is dedicated to sustainable fashion practices, incorporating organic fabrics and maintaining environmental consciousness. He also want a better representation of diverse woman on the Catwalk.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="799" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/34AE9546-17ED-43EB-8CBB-92105558C619.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-114" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/34AE9546-17ED-43EB-8CBB-92105558C619.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/34AE9546-17ED-43EB-8CBB-92105558C619-240x300.jpg 240w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/34AE9546-17ED-43EB-8CBB-92105558C619-508x634.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Myself with Model Emilia boateng</figcaption></figure>



<p>The British Fashion Council (BFC), recognises that the fashion industry engages consumers daily. Therefore, through the Institute of Positive Fashion (IPF), their aim is to create an industry blueprint by bringing together expertise from different areas to help brands with a platform designed to celebrate industry best practice and encourage future business decisions to create positive change.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="853" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8928.png" alt="" class="wp-image-115" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8928.png 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8928-225x300.png 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8928-508x677.png 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">With the British Designer Ozwald Boateng and his daughter Emilia boateng</figcaption></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/julien-macdonald-obe-celebrates-authentic-beauty/">Julien Macdonald OBE Celebrates Authentic Beauty</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/julien-macdonald-obe-celebrates-authentic-beauty/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Exquisite Fashion Show by Paul Costelloe</title>
		<link>/the-exquisite-fashion-show-by-paul-costelloe/</link>
					<comments>/the-exquisite-fashion-show-by-paul-costelloe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Let me acquaint you with another prominent figure, namely Paul Costelloe. He stands as one of the most well-established figures in British and Irish Fashion, renowned for his...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-exquisite-fashion-show-by-paul-costelloe/">The Exquisite Fashion Show by Paul Costelloe</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Let me acquaint you with another prominent figure, namely Paul Costelloe. He stands as one of the most well-established figures in British and Irish Fashion, renowned for his utilization of handcrafted, opulent fabrics intertwined with cutting-edge design, innovation, and creativity. He pursued his education at the École d&#8217;Chambre Syndicale de la Haute Couture, Paris, from 1968 to 1969.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="634" height="429" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20190922-WA0013-e1704719754919.jpg" alt="The Exquisite Fashion Show by Paul Costelloe" class="wp-image-106" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20190922-WA0013-e1704719754919.jpg 634w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20190922-WA0013-e1704719754919-300x203.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG-20190922-WA0013-e1704719754919-508x344.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 634px) 100vw, 634px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Myself with Paul Costelloe.</figcaption></figure>



<p>The fashion show event for this season took place at the Palm Court in The Waldorf Hilton Hotel. I had the honour of being invited as a front-row guest, and it proved to be an extraordinary display featuring vibrant colours. The new collection emanates a blend of vibrancy, sophistication, effortless femininity, and elegance. The models showcased trendy curls styled by Sharon Tate, presenting a 60s-inspired look that was nothing short of fabulous. Complemented by unique, oversized gold bangles and pearl jewellery from Pebble London, along with powerful and colourful footwear, the entire ensemble was captivating. Personally, I found the shoes particularly delightful. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="799" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-799x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-105" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-799x1024.jpg 799w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-234x300.jpg 234w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-768x984.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956-508x651.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8956.jpg 809w" sizes="(max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px" /></figure>



<p>In conclusion, the experience served as a reminder to &#8220;keep heels, head, and standards high,&#8221; echoing the timeless words of the late and great Coco Chanel.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="586" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952-586x1024.jpg" alt="The Exquisite Fashion Show by Paul Costelloe" class="wp-image-108" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952-586x1024.jpg 586w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952-172x300.jpg 172w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952-508x888.jpg 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_8952.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 586px) 100vw, 586px" /></figure>



<p>For the grand finale, visit my <a href="https://www.instagram.com/victoriakafifi/" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.instagram.com/victoriakafifi/">https://www.instagram.com/victoriakafifi/</a> for exclusive videos providing an inside look at the highlights of this fantastic event.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-exquisite-fashion-show-by-paul-costelloe/">The Exquisite Fashion Show by Paul Costelloe</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-exquisite-fashion-show-by-paul-costelloe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Embracing True Beauty: A Celebration of Authenticity.</title>
		<link>/embracing-true-beauty-a-celebration-of-authenticity/</link>
					<comments>/embracing-true-beauty-a-celebration-of-authenticity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=49</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Authentic beauty can have different meanings among individuals, it’s about being true to one’s true self, embracing imperfections and flaws. Beauty is like art, there are no pieces...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/embracing-true-beauty-a-celebration-of-authenticity/">Embracing True Beauty: A Celebration of Authenticity.</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<p>Authentic beauty can have different meanings among individuals, it’s about being true to one’s true self, embracing imperfections and flaws. Beauty is like art, there are no pieces of art that are identical. Similarly, there is no beauty without imperfection, and each individual possesses their own distinctive form of beauty. Therefore, individuals should acknowledge and confidently embrace their imperfections unapologetically, as these imperfections are an integral aspect of beauty. It is important to recognise that each individual possesses intrinsic worth, independent of societal beauty standards that fail to celebrate this uniqueness.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-1024x1024.jpg" alt="London Fashion Week" class="wp-image-51" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-768x768.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-2048x2048.jpg 2048w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-88x88.jpg 88w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-973x973.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0575-508x508.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">London Fashion Week</figcaption></figure>



<p>Analogous to art, beauty is diverse and attempting to conform to conventional beauty norms is a suppression, denying the diverse expressions of beauty. True beauty begins with self- acceptance, and originates from within, reflecting the essence of your character through the choices you make, how you present yourself, and how you treat others. Therefore, let us celebrate our skills, abilities, talents, intellect rather than placing emphasis on superficial aspects such as body size, skin colour, and conforming to societal beauty standards. In contrast, let us spread awareness and encourage mental fitness and well-being, body positivity, self care, and the importance of human connection. This involves actively engaging in listening, caring, expressing love towards one another.</p>



<p>There should be more celebration and appreciation of the many forms that complete what beauty, including: the acts of kindness, love, respect, honesty and loyalty. Reflecting on cultures throughout history, it becomes evident that beauty can finds its foundation in morality, integrity, kindness, loyalty and faith. These were once universal virtues and values shared collectively. Regrettably, this commonality has waned, at least in widespread acceptance. This is unfortunate because a life without a moral compass, individuals may find themselves adrift. A predicament already faced by many, but let us find solace in the fact that not everyone is lost. As uniquely and beautifully made individuals, we ought to re-embrace the shared values, principles, and faith that were once woven into the fabric of our existence. This is what holds significance and will continue to bind us together. Holding steadfast to the principles of truthfulness, compassion, and forbearance is paramount.</p>





<p>I would assert that authentic beauty is inseparable from true happiness. The act of being loved and accepted for who you are empowers you to embrace your beauty—a state of untarnished joy reminiscent of a child. The right to happiness is inherent to all, and there exists a moral obligation to embrace this birthright. True beauty thrives in the richness of diversity. To quote singer, songwriter, Britt Nicole: “let’s focus on being pretty kind, pretty funny, pretty smart and pretty strong” rather than solely on external appearances.</p>



<p>Additionally, I would appreciate hearing your insight, my beloved readers. What does authentic beauty truly mean to you?</p>



<p>With love Victoria</p>
<p>The post <a href="/embracing-true-beauty-a-celebration-of-authenticity/">Embracing True Beauty: A Celebration of Authenticity.</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/embracing-true-beauty-a-celebration-of-authenticity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating Diversity in Fashion</title>
		<link>/celebrating-diversity-in-fashion/</link>
					<comments>/celebrating-diversity-in-fashion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=71</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As a society, we have made significant strides to adapt to changes, embrace diversity, and appreciate individual uniqueness. For example, there is currently a diverse array of models...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/celebrating-diversity-in-fashion/">Celebrating Diversity in Fashion</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As a society, we have made significant strides to adapt to changes, embrace diversity, and appreciate individual uniqueness. For example, there is currently a diverse array of models of colour on the runways, a significant increase from when I initially entered the modelling profession. At the time, it appeared that only one or two spots were available for ethnic models on each runway. A notable shift is occurring, focusing on empowering the next generation of young Black women who were once disregarded but are now being acknowledged and told that they too matter.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1005" height="640" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-66" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1.jpg 1005w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1-300x191.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1-768x489.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1-973x620.jpg 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/FB_IMG_1549809136426-1-508x324.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 1005px) 100vw, 1005px" /></figure>



<p>Increased awareness about diversity and inclusion, especially regarding the representation of women of colour in the fashion industry, has been widely discussed in the mainstream media. However, it&#8217;s crucial to distinguish between desiring inclusion and advocating for a complete overhaul of the exclusive system. Despite the ongoing journey and the need for more efforts, it&#8217;s important to acknowledge and celebrate the positive changes achieved so far.</p>



<p>Thanks to those who paved the way, we can now observe firsthand the transformation taking place in the fashion world. It is a triumph that this transformation is underway, even though it is happening gradually. In the Autumn/Winter 2019 shows, the visibility of the change and its progression seemed more significant, marking a notable shift in the fashion industry towards becoming a more naturally inclusive space, with promising prospects for the future.</p>



<p>Prominent figures, such as Pierpaolo Piccioli, serve as excellent examples of the practical implications of this change. During the couture season in Paris, Piccioli demonstrated a commitment to diversity by predominantly casting black models for his magnificent, colourful, feminine, and stunning Valentino collection. This historic move empowered Black women to confidently embrace their beauty without reservation. The presentation was not just a passing trend but a significant statement and stance, asserting that black women have always been a powerful presence and continue to demonstrate their capability. The myth that women of colour cannot effectively influence and sell has been debunked, as evidenced by the recent elevation of models of colour as cover girls on Vogue magazine.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="799" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0705.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-74" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0705.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0705-240x300.jpg 240w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/IMG_0705-508x634.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></figure>



<p>Witnessing diverse women featured on the front cover, irrespective of their age, race, abilities, and ethnicity, proved to be genuinely inspiring. I take immense pride in the achievements at British Vogue, where the work underscored the significance of diversity and inclusion within the fashion industry. Appreciation goes to the distinguished Edward Enninful, the editor-in-chief for British Vogue, He truly exemplifies legendary status.</p>



<p>I believe and agree that beauty is diverse, and the fashion industry must acknowledge the influence of showcasing a broader spectrum of beauty. It should serve as a platform for diversity that promotes inclusivity in an exclusive manner. Representation in media and other services is crucial for everyone to see themselves. Brands should also cater to a wide demographic range because when people witness diversity in high fashion modelling, it becomes easier for them to relate to the collections.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/celebrating-diversity-in-fashion/">Celebrating Diversity in Fashion</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/celebrating-diversity-in-fashion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Queen Elizabeth II Award for British Designers</title>
		<link>/queen-elizabeth-ii-award-for-british-designers/</link>
					<comments>/queen-elizabeth-ii-award-for-british-designers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[victoria.kafifi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[creative industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion shows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London Fashion Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monarchy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London fashion week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queen Elizabeth II Award for British Designers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the most thrilling moment of my career was meeting her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II. Her Majesty the Queen made an astonishing surprise appearance at London Fashion...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/queen-elizabeth-ii-award-for-british-designers/">Queen Elizabeth II Award for British Designers</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="960" height="720" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830.jpg" alt="Queen Elizabeth II" class="wp-image-42" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Vicky1830-508x381.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Queen Elizabeth II suprise appearance at London Fashion Week</figcaption></figure>



<p><em>One of the most thrilling moment of my career was meeting her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II. Her Majesty the Queen made an astonishing surprise appearance at London Fashio</em>n week. She was accompanied by Caroline Rush, the Chief Executive of the British Fashion Council, who guided her through the venue, observing presentations of various designers&#8217; collections during London Fashion Week. Her Majesty took the time to visit each designer, engaging in conversations. Her purpose for attending London Fashion Week was to bestow the inaugural Queen Elizabeth 2 Award for British design.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="742" height="512" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Designer.jpg" alt="Queen Elizabeth II" class="wp-image-44" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Designer.jpg 742w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Designer-300x207.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Queen-Designer-508x351.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 742px) 100vw, 742px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Queen Elizabeth II, first appearance at London Fashion Week</figcaption></figure>



<p>Seated in the front row alongside Anna Wintour, Vogue&#8217;s editor-in-chief, her presence captivated the crowd, prompting them to rise in greeting. Her Majesty watched the show with a composed demeanor and excitement in her eyes. She adorned herself in an ice-blue skirt suit, complemented by a black handbag, black gloves, and black footwear. She even shared a light-hearted moment with Anna Wintour, resulting in both of them laughing and smiling.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="960" height="720" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-46" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Model-vicky-_1834-508x381.jpg 508w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<p>After the show, in recognition of his achievements, Her Majesty presented Richard Quinn with the inaugural Queen Elizabeth II Award for British Design.The British-born designer is known for specialising in womenswear and printed textiles.Remarkably, he manages a print studio in Peckham, situated in south London, which is accessible to both fellow designers and college students.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="victoriakafifi 1519208985 1719570765898092315 371999188" width="620" height="465" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8ht3cYkiWa4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The Queen engaging with designers</figcaption></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/queen-elizabeth-ii-award-for-british-designers/">Queen Elizabeth II Award for British Designers</a> appeared first on <a href="">Victoria Kafifi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/queen-elizabeth-ii-award-for-british-designers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
